## Miguel Angel Gonzalez Yepes

#### **Software Engineer**

nationality: spanish

date of birth: 21-12-1976 mobile: +34 649981912

email: magonye@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with many years of experience developing applications in several sectors: consultancy, tourism, pharmaceutical/hospital, retail & e-commerce and finance.

In constant evolution, I never stop learning and questioning myself as a professional.

A practitioner of agile methodologies and XP.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### ZOPA, Software Engineer June 2018-Present

Working in an autonomous cross functional team. Designing and coding a distributed system to allow customers to have savings products. Using best technology possible and always evolving and learning. Huge lover of Kafka, micro-services, testing and clean and simple code.

My team build a system, formed by several services, from scratch, and in charge of all Savings products of the Bank. All services were containerized and ran in a container cluster, and using asynchronous communication mechanism. Our services were also connected to other company services, managed by different teams. A lot of focus to build a resilient, trustable and stable system, as we were expecting to manage a huge volume of accounts and money in our system.

### MANGO, Software Engineer July 2012-June 2018

Since 2016, working on Payments Team, a cross-functional team, with the main goal of providing the easiest, more reliable, safer and most flexible payment experience to all Mango Online customers.

We're running the following practices and activities:

- · Building autonomous services for payment and refund flows.
- TDD
- · Pair Programming
- Code-review
- · Daily and weekly meetings
- DevOps culture, building our own CI/CD pipeline
- Owners of all development cycle: from the design phase to deploy to production
- Creating a culture of learning: preparing weekly sessions of knowledge sharing across teams, lunch and learn sessions within the team and a book-club initiative.

Before that, I participated also on:

- Integration with Marketplaces, such as Amazon, Zalando, TMall, LaRedoute, Lotte...
- Development and maintenance of the back-office application.
- Improvements in different processes of the company, such as efficiency and performance.

## GRIFOLS, Software Analyst April 2008-July 2012

Software Analyst in hospital and laboratory projects in Java / J2EE.

Participation in all phases of the project, from the collection of functional requirements, through the development of design specifications, design of unit tests and the design of the data model.

· Development of projects using the methodology in V.

- TDD (Test Driven Development).
- Continuous integration

## HOTUSA, Java Analyst/Programmer February 2003-April 2008

- Programming in Oracle Java and PL / SQL language.
- Responsible for the GDS (Global Distribution System) environment. In 2004-2005 I made the connection
  through the Pegasus switch to the GDS, consisting of the creation of the availability module and the link
  with our existing reservation system.
- · Internet booking system for travel agencies.
- XML availability services and reserves for third parties.
- · Rate change system for hotels via the Web.
- Internal applications for managing and updating data between reservation and availability system and databases, fax reports, monitoring ports, etc.
- Application for the maintenance of databases: hotels, reservations, travel agencies.

### IT DEUSTO, PHP & Java Developer March 1999-February 2003

- · Programming in PHP and Java.
- Programming an infinity of dynamic Web pages, with database persistence, and administrable by the clients.
- · Intranets for companies, with document managers, agendas, project monitoring.

### GENERAL CABLE, Systems Department Intern February 1998-March 1999

- Maintenance of computers, email systems, backup copies, etc. both the computers of the headquarters of Barcelona, and the factories of Manlleu and Montcada.
- Trips for the set-up of commercial delegations in Valencia and Madrid.
- Realization of internal computer applications for the department.

## **EDUCATION**

**COMPUTER ENGINEER (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya - Facultat d'Informàtica de Barcelona)** 1995 - 2000

### OTHER COURSES AND TRAININGS

- Using Kubernetes as a Developer Pluralsight 2020
- · Kotlin Bootcamp for Programmers Udacity 2018
- Functional Programming Principles in Scala EPFL 2017
- Crafting Code Sandro Mancuso (Codurance) 2016
- Deploying to AWS Training Mashooq Badar (Codurance) 2016
- MongoDB Essentials Training MongoDB 2015
- MongoDB for Java Developers MongoDB 2015

I usually like to attend different meetups and coding dojos in Barcelona, and some conferences as well, balancing it with my family and personal life.

## **SKILLS**

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

- Java & Kotlin
- · Build tools: Maven & Gradle
- Messaging Systems: Apache Kafka & AWS SQS
- · Containers: Docker & Kubernetes
- · Automation server: Jenkins
- · Databases: Oracle, MS SQL and PostgreSQL

### **WORKFLOW**

- · Cross Functional Teams
- · Agile Development & Scrum
- Extreme Programming
- Automation lover
- · Team player

# **INTERESTS**

I'm the father of two incredible kids: Adrià (2005) and Claudia (2008). I love to spend as much time as I can with them, as well as with my wife Geraldine.

Other things I love to do are:

- training: I'm a huge fan of bodyweight workouts.
- reading: Both technical and fiction books are my favs. You can find me in goodreads
- tv series: I love to watch tv series with my family, only with my wife or even alone. There's always a good show for every occasion.
- walking with my dogs: I have two dogs and I love to walk with them in the mountains.